<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King and Queen, a proclamation for appointing commissioners for putting in execution an act of this present Parliament for raising money by a poll and otherwise, towards the reducing of Ireland, and prosecuting the war against France William R.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A66293</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing W2583</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R23264</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12494844</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12494844</idno>
            <idno type="VID">62472</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A66293)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 62472)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 951:53)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King and Queen, a proclamation for appointing commissioners for putting in execution an act of this present Parliament for raising money by a poll and otherwise, towards the reducing of Ireland, and prosecuting the war against France William R.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary)</author>
                  <author>William III, King of England, 1650-1702.</author>
                  <author>Mary II, Queen of England, 1662-1694.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Charles Bill and Thomas Newcomb ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
                  <note>Broadside.</note>
                  <note>At end of text: Given at our court at Whitehall the thirteenth day of May, 1690.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Act for raising money by a poll payable quarterly for one year for carrying on a vigorous war against France.</term>
               <term>England and Wales. --  Act for granting to Their Majesties an aid of four shillings in the pound for one year for carrying on a vigorous war against France.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1689-1702 --  Sources.</term>
               <term>Broadsides</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-03</date>
            <label>Elspeth Healey</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Rekeyed and resubmitted</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="royal_proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:62472:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 1 -->
            <head>By the King and Queen, A PROCLAMATION For Appointing Commiſſioners for putting in Execution an Act of this preſent Parliament for Raiſing Money by a Poll and otherwiſe, towards the Reducing of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and Proſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuting the War againſt <hi>France.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <signed>WILLIAM R.</signed>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas in and by one Act lately Paſſed in this preſent Parliament (Entituled, <hi>An Act for Raiſing Money by a Poll and otherwiſe, towards the Reducing of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and Proſecuting the War againſt <hi>France</hi>
               </hi>) it is Enacted, That for the better Aſſeſſing, Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering, and Levying of the ſeveral Sums of Money limitted and appointed to be paid by the ſaid Act, and for the more effectual putting of the ſame in Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, the Perſons named and appointed to be Commiſſioners by an Act of the laſt Parliament (Entituled, <hi>An Act for a Grant to Their Majeſties of an Aid of Two ſhillings in the Pound for One Year</hi>) together With thoſe Members of this Preſent Houſe of Commons, which were not named Commiſſioners in the ſaid Act, ſhall be Commiſſioners for putting in Execution the ſaid Act for Raiſing Money by a Poll and otherwiſe, and the Powers therein contained, within all and every the ſeveral and reſpective Counties, Ridings, Cities, Boroughs, Towns and Places for which they ſhall be appointed Commiſſioners reſpectively, as by the ſaid Act, relation being thereunto had, more fully may appear. The King and Queéns moſt Excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent Majeſties repoſing eſpecial Truſt and Confidence in the Abilities, Care and Circumſpections of all and every the Perſon and Perſons which were named and appointed to be Commiſſioners by the ſaid Act for granting to Their Majeſties an Aid of Two ſhillings in the Pound, That are now living, do hereby Appoint and Declare them and every of them to be Their Commiſſioners for putting in Execution the ſaid Act of this <gap reason="illegible: in crease" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> and all the Powers therein and contained, within all and every the ſeveral and reſpective Counties, Ridings, Cities Boroughs, Towns and Places for which by the ſaid former Act they are appointed Commiſſioners. And Their Majeſties Repoſing the like Truſt and Confidence in the Care and Circumſpections of thoſe Members of this preſent Houſe of Commons which there not named Commiſſioners in the ſaid Act, do by theſe Preſents likewiſe Appoint and Declare them to be alſo Commiſſioners for putting in Execution the ſaid Act for Raiſing Money by a Poll and otherwiſe, and all the Powers therein contained, within the ſeveral Counties, Cities and Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roughs for which they reſpectively ſerve in this preſent Parliament; and where they or any of them do ſerve for any particular Cities, Boroughs, or Ports, they ſhall act as Commiſſioners for the reſpective Counties in which ſuch Cities, Boroughs, or Ports are; And to them the ſaid Commiſſioners, or to ſuch or ſo many of them as by the ſaid Act for Raiſing Money by a Poll and otherwiſe, are or ſhall be in any Caſe or Caſes requiſite and neceſſary, Their Majeſties do hereby give full Power and Authority to put Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion all the Powers contained or ſpecified in the ſame Act, and generally to Do, Perform and Execute, or cauſe to be Done, Performed or Executed, all Matters or Things whatſoever, which any Commiſſioners appointed or to be appointed by Their Majeſties, may or can lawfully Do, Perform or Execute, in rela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to the ſame, within all and every of the ſaid ſeveral and reſpective Counties, Ridings, Cities, Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roughs, Towns and Places for which they are Commiſſioned and Appointed, as aforeſaid: Hereby Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling and Requiring them and every of them from time to time to Proceed and Act according to the Rules and Directions of the ſaid Act of Parliament, and diligently to intend the Execution of this Their Majeſties Service as becometh. And this ſhall be to them and every of them a ſufficient Warrant and Diſcharge in this behalf.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given at Our Court at <hi>Whitehall</hi> 
                  <date>the Thirteenth Day of <hi>May,</hi> 1690. In the Second Year of Our Reign.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
God ſave King William and Queen Mary.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>Charles Bill</hi> and <hi>Thomas Newcomb,</hi> Printers to the King and Queens moſt Excellent Majeſties. 1690.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
